so one of the questions that's relevant
to what we're talking about right now it
says here um and let's see I don't
remember who the question is I like to
give credit where credit is due um but
I'm just going to go ahead and read it
it says can you talk a little bit more
about the different
professions uh and how to
prepare in one of your videos you talked
about being a software engineer when the
Market's good and then operations when
the Market's rough uh there is another
video about that how to survive late
stage capitalism and how to you know
where are the blacksmith jobs those are
the two videos on that uh for someone
who's having to manage what to study
what do you suggest uh focusing on one
profession or trying to do both at the
same time um and again this is house ho
ho JoJo uh asking the question the
answer honestly
is I don't know I'm I'm sorry that
you're going to make a whole video about
this um you my career kind of happened
to me on accident with regard to that
and all I can do is share you my
experience as a mentor and I encourage
you to ask other people who have had
similar experience so I I've told the
story in the video in one of those
videos I already told the story but it's
just a matter of learning what it took
to get the job right and and um you know
I I started out a software developer
make you know making web pages because I
I knew that the future would be web
pages and I got a job for internet
service provider because I knew how to
do background tags in Netscape I kid you
not and because it was such a small
organization end up becoming the
director of sales and the Web Master all
at the same time um and I still have
stock in that stock in that company
fibernet you know somewhere and um so I
taught myself HTML and there was a CSS
in order to to get that job and I did
you know the web development and that
was enough to wow you know the the
people that are running the organization
and give me the job build that trust
that I talk about in another video and
and then I mean I I I I did all that on
I I did all that coding like in textmate
on my Mac in Pearl how my S Pearl in 21
days uh from a book and knew that coding
was going to be a thing um so I guess
the answer to your question
is pick up relevant Lang languages uh
and learn them you're going to have to
learn to code no matter what so you know
which one should you do first I don't
know that that really matters um the
beginner boost just to to to you know
put a bullet point in this we are this
year we're going to do learn to code in
Python and JavaScript at the same time
so if you've never coded before at all
um that's a good time to do that uh
we're also going to do uh coding in HTML
and markdown and CSS which is totally
different uh than you know application
web applications development um which I
by the way I don't recommend anybody go
into web applications development unless
that's truly what you want to do uh
that's kind of a secondary decision um
uh you know there's it's a great it's a
great career but it's it's it's not
necessarily uh going to be compatible
with operations um so I honestly I think
you can do the same both at the same
time and and I think what you want to do
is you want to start building your home
lab um and that's going to there's
another video we're going to make about
whether you should build a home lab or
build one in the cloud and that is a
very important question we'll get to
that next and but I feel like you can do
that now I feel like you can you know
start with a VM and start coding on the
thing and learning about how to set up
your own network uh you know setting up
your own virtual machine understanding
what in I think you can do the same at
the both I'm really try I'm not trying
to cop out here I I feel like you can do
both at the same time um and uh uh yeah
I mean that that's it hopefully
hopefully that helps uh maybe not